This FBI agent is going undercover... and he's concealing more than a weapon.
Big Momma's House is a crime, comedy film directed by Raja Gosnell.
When a street-smart FBI agent is sent to Georgia to protect a beautiful single mother and her son from an escaped
convict, he is forced to impersonate a crass Southern granny known as Big Momma in order to remain incognito.
Malcolm Turner, played by Martin Lawrence.
Sherry Pierce, played by Nia Long.
John, played by Paul Giamatti.
Trent Pierce, played by Jascha Washington.
Lester Vesco, played by Terrence Howard.
Nolan, played by Anthony Anderson.
Big Momma's House is a 2000 crime comedy film, directed by Raja
Gosnell, and written by Darryl Quarles and Don Rhymer.
The film stars Martin Lawrence as an FBI agent who is tasked with tracking down an escaped convict and his loot, by going
undercover as the estranged grandmother of the convict's former girlfriend, unaware of the bond he will form with her.
The film also stars Nia Long, Paul Giamatti, and Terrence Howard.
Big Momma's House received mostly negative reviews from
critics, but grossed over $174 million worldwide.
Its success led to two sequels: Big Momma's House 2 (2006)
and Big Mommas: Like Father, Like Son (2011).
The film explores themes of undercover, fbi, disguise, impersonation.
The tone is lighthearted.